[Music]
yes
stuff
[Music]
hey everyone my name is danang bolsara
folks like to call me d for short and
i'm
joined by my lovely assistant minnie
griff right now we're here
to be your host for the event this live
event
of the menu life and td insurance
director's fundraising challenge
presented
by swish maintenance now before we get
into tonight's live event
we want to take a moment to recognize
the land that we are currently
on here at the university in guelph and
during that time i also encourage those
participating today online
to think about and reflect the le on the
land that you
are currently residing on wherever you
are
all right it has been a very exciting
and busy week for
our department the athletic department
and our student athletes with our
four-day push
to raise funds for our student athletic
scholarships
now due to covet 19 the department has
had to cancel
several of the fundraising events which
help fund the scholarships for our
athletes this coming year
particularly the president's golf
tournament which has always been a
successful
fundraising support since 2007.
and that's why we're here today with the
manulife and td insurance
directors fundraising challenge
presented by swish maintenance
now a hundred percent okay i'm not
talking about
45 85 not even 99 i'm talking about 100
of the proceeds of the money received
throughout this challenge will go
directly
to fund those athletes who are counting
on these scholarships this year
to kick off this wonderful party i would
like
to pay tribute to our griffin student
athletes by watching our launch
video sponsored by harbridge and cross
a year in review of our griffins
put me on the stage now i'm ready to
rage now
i feel like an animal stuck in a cage
and i'm ready to break out
my time my time none of you people can
tell me to stop
this time like the last time you better
yeah so what are you afraid of those
feelings are made up
get in the game your moment of fame show
them what you're made of
it's time that we stand up it's time
that we stand up
for anyone asking who is the best we
putting our
don't be surprised i'll take on
so turn me up real loud my time my time
none of you people can tell me to stop
lower the lights down
hand over my crown hand over my heart
[Music]
reaching
i thought so turn me up real loud
all right welcome back everyone what
another memorable year for the griffins
and thank you to get thank you again
sorry to harbridge and cross
our sponsor for the launch video we
appreciate your
support now we're here today to
fundraise
for our student athletic scholarships
and to thank those
that have shown their support to the
initiative by giving and sponsoring
this challenge now if you're watching
today and you're wondering how
you can help it's quite easy all you got
to do is visit griffins.ca
dfc once again that's griffins.ca
d fc and you can see it's here on the
bottom here
if you forget it's uh it's quite easy
and to donate is quite simple as well so
we would appreciate
any donations that come through we
appreciate all the support for all that
are able to donate and help our student
athletes also if you're watching today
please give a high be engaging let me
know how good i look in this soon you
know i'd love to hear from all of you
so we can't have a director's
fundraising challenge
without a director so it's my pleasure
at this time to introduce
scott mcroberts your director of
athletics
[Music]
hi i'm scott mcrobers and it's my honor
to be the director of athletics here at
the university of guelph
on behalf of the department of athletics
our many coaches to support our student
athletes day in day out
and our 750 varsity athletes i'm proud
to represent the guelph griffin
i just want to take this opportunity to
thank you for your generous support the
sponsors
the donors and for all those people that
took part in the online directors
challenge
for fundraising for our student athletes
this money that is providing the support
you provided to this week
is more important than ever in
supporting our student athletes for this
upcoming year
thank you to the generous sponsors who
stepped up to champion this event
td financial and manulife our title
sponsors thank you so much and our
presenting sponsor
swish we appreciate the support that
you've given us for this event
unfortunately do the cobia 19 pandemic
we are seeing a shortfall this year in
our scholarship money
some people couldn't make their
donations some people had to put their
donations on hold
and we understand people's financial
situations
in the job market so we are a hundred
thousand dollars short this year of
providing over 150 student athletes
their scholarship money
and we're here today to help raise that
money in the coming weeks
to get to our goal these scholarships
are critical to our student athletes
many of them are spending 35 to 48 hours
a week both training in their sport
and in their academics representing a 70
to 80 hour
week on those two fronts this money to
support them
allows them to do these things
concentrate on their studies and their
sport
but also to be able to provide them
opportunities to gain valuable skills
to work in the community and volunteer
at schools
representing our griffin brand and
working with our junior griffins at the
same time
the importance of the scholarship money
allows those to flourish
it allows them to continue to be a
student
and an athlete at the same time and for
that i thank you i am so proud of our
student athletes
we are a record number of student
athletes are now achieving 80
or better in their academics and a big
part of that
is the support that you provide to them
and lastly
thank you to all our student athletes
you are the reason
why we are here today and we hope you
are well and safe at this time
[Music]
thank you very much scott also thank you
karen for that
comment i appreciate that you notice all
right let's continue on schedule here
student athletes have a grueling
schedule they spend
so much of their time training
practicing
studying which does not allow all of
them to have part-time jobs
while also going to school these
scholarships allow them to focus on
their sport
their training and their studies and
give them
and gives them sorry financial security
and a little bit of peace of mind
without our sponsors and donors this
week and for those that are donating
online right now
we could not make this happen without
you
firstly we'd like to recognize our title
sponsors
manulife and td insurance and our
presenting sponsor for this live event
swish maintenance your ongoing support
for our student athlete scholarships
through our fundraising event
is what helps drive our programs every
year so thank you once again
now i'd like to introduce one of our
title sponsors alex lucas senior vice
president and head of
individual insurance for manulife and a
proud ug
alumni to say a few words
hi everyone this is alex lucas the head
of individual insurance for many life in
canada and a former guelph griffin
we're very excited to once again sponsor
your efforts to raise money for student
athletes
it aligns perfectly with malek's mission
of lives made better
and it's even more important during
these times of a pandemic economic
crisis
and social discord that we band together
to do things for each other and our
communities
like this program may life is the
innovator in the industry you can apply
for up to a million dollars of insurance
without intrusive nursing visits
or we've recently added virtual doctor
visits through webex
i'm disappointed i can't join you for an
in-person event this year i had a lot of
fun last year
but i know as guelph griffins you'll do
a great job fundraising through this
virtual event
best of luck in the fundraising campaign
and i wish all of you a safe
and happy remainder of 2020.
[Music]
thanks alex and thank you again to
manulife and td insurance
our title sponsors and of course swish
maintenance
our presenting sponsor now before we
continue on
we've got some interactive things going
on here and i want to draw your
attention to the screen
around me all right so if you look right
up here if i can point yeah there we go
right there
we have our keysweater excavating
countdown clock
so this countdown clock it shows you the
time until the end of the challenge
and our fundraising ticker which is down
below to show you our current title
as a total sorry as it stands of right
now so we
are at 55
seventy five dollars so far so that
number is quite impressive but let's see
how much more
we can get so again our keysweater
countdown clock right here
and we have our total right here as well
all right so let's continue to move on
here
so last year the department handed okay
are you ready for this
handed out 500 000
in scholarship funds helping a total of
student athletes currently this year we
have a shortfall of about a hundred
thousand dollars
that's why we're hosting this event and
this challenge to help
close that gap and so we're able to help
provide
our athletes with scholarships that we
have committed to them
now the cost of being a student gets
more expensive each year and the
scholarships we provide help support
them financially
and help them succeed on and off the
field
now we're going to hear from a few of
our student athletes who have sent a
message from their homes to tell you
how important scholarships are to them
and to show you what a difference those
funds can make so
thank you to ernst young llp our student
athlete
video sponsor
[Music]
hello griff nation my name is iphone
jolac i'm a student athlete here at the
university of guelph
for the sport of football and today i
want to take the time to ask you to
consider supporting university of guelph
student athletes through the directors
fundraising challenge
i personally have greatly benefited from
scholarships because they've allowed me
to spend less time focusing on my
financials and more time focusing on my
athletics my academics
and my volunteer commitments being a
griffin athlete comes with many
commitments
and in order to fully invest in your
sport you have to
make time for self-care
practices competitions and recovery back
three years ago when i came to guelph as
an ncaa transfer
i was just hoping to have any sort of a
student athlete experience at home
and the experience i've been given by
the university of guelph on all fronts
has absolutely exceeded every
expectation i could have had walking
in because of my scholarships i've been
able to steadily increase my academic
average
improve my athletic performance and
spend more time in my community working
with youth girls soccer teams
and trying to decrease food insecurity
in the guelph area
thanks to your generous contributions
university of guelph student athletes
can focus and maintain their personal
goals in their respective sport
while also maintaining high academic
standing in their respective program
it has also allowed me to attend
training camps high level training camps
that i might not have otherwise had the
opportunity to
as well as access ist and physio
services that are really important
to preventing injuries your generous
support
allows university of guelph student
athletes to be known as some of the best
athletes
across the country because we are
fortunate enough to have the time to
focus on maintaining elite status
in our sport without compromising on our
education because we know
that education is the most important
part about being a student athlete
i'm forever grateful for the
opportunities that my scholarships have
provided me
thank you for your consideration and i'd
like to encourage you to visit
griffins.ca backslash dfc to give today
thank you thank you so much for your
time god bless
and i hope to see you on the football
field soon go griffin
sponsor videos video sponsor no hop up
higher
all right thank you zoe aphram andrew
and cyan
we appreciate you sharing your messages
and thank you again to ernst
young llp our student video
sponsor all right so during that break
uh we managed to get some more donations
and totaling
2 500 so
thank you once again to those who have
been contributing
and as you can see our total now is
fifty eight
thousand seventy five dollars so that's
fifty eight thousand
seventy five dollars and again thank you
for those donations
and keep them coming we wanna get that
ticker going here all right so we have
great student athletes right
that's a complete no-brainer we have
incredible athletes here at the
university of guelph
but you know what we also have we have
great fans
without our griffin fans there would be
empty seats
no energy no excitement griffin fans
packed the stadiums they packed the
arenas they packed the fields
even in the pouring rain to cheer on our
teams
so we thought it would be appropriate to
pay
tribute to you so see next for our fan
[Music]
video
hey
[Music]
uh
oh
[Music]
uh
i miss live events and more importantly
i miss those fans
we can't wait to get back in front of
you and host you of course here on the
university of guelph campus all right so
i kind of want to do a clock update so
if you look at the time here we've got
a 16 50 left to go here uh
for this live event and of course folks
you guys have been donating generously
and if you
if you want to be a part of that uh
follow the link here griffins.ca
dfc again that's griffins.ca dfc
anything you can contribute is very very
much appreciated
all right so last year was another
memorable and banner year for our
griffins teams all right so
here's the numbers all right so you can
write this down if you want to we got
two national championships and five
conference titles 104 student athletes
earned
oua all-star status and 51 student
athletes received youth sports canadian
status
and wait i got more free all right and
over 25
of our griffin athletes finished with
academic awards so
griffin athletes if you're watching
right now pad yourself
on the back and as also if you're
watching as a fan let's give those
griffin athletes a round of applause as
well so each year
at the end of the year is our annual
athletic banquet it's one of my favorite
times of the year and it's an easy
excuse to get dressed up right so
at the athletic banquet we award one top
moment of the year
obviously there's a plethora of big
moments throughout the course of the
year
but we wind it down to a total of four
and we like to hand out what we like to
call the griffey awards so
last year uh we had four incredible
moments that happened
in the year and uh we're gonna share
those with you right now
tonight so let's see those griffy videos
[Applause]
now picked up and taken advantage of
mcmillan used her height there to take
advantage of let's see if she can get
something here
let's see if we can get something there
we go
there we go that was a nice nice goal
by macmillan who used here
[Music]
well here we go
and he's gonna fall on it and he's in a
touchdown
it is are you kidding me as i
live and breathe the unbelievable
has happened back at yoga and they are
dancing up a storm
[Music]
valentini charges
go crazy
[Music]
so
oh
[Music]
[Applause]
so
[Music]
oh man four equally incredible moments i
can't imagine how hard it was just to
pick one as the winner
and unfortunately there can only be one
winner and if you're curious who won
our griffey this year it was the queen's
cup hockey overtime
ot for the ages and if you were there
that night that night was
incredible unforgettable not one not two
but three
overtime so again congratulations to our
men
for being queen's cup champions this
year and of course winning the griffey
all right so behind our successful
student athletes are
our incredible coaching staff now we're
now we have a few messages from our
griffin coaches and this is brought to
you by
capital paving
my name is shantique carrie payne head
coach of the guelph griffin swim team
i'm here today asking for your help to
support our student athletes through the
director's fundraising challenge
at any given year we do a number of
fundraising events
to help alleviate the financial burden
for our student athletes coven 19
really took the wind out of our sails
due to the pandemic
many of our students lost their jobs or
were unable to attain employment
your help will be greatly appreciated
your donation allows athletes to commit
their time to training and academics
without also having to work a part-time
job to fund their education
for many of our athletes and the
programs they're in
having a part-time job and playing
volleyball is extremely difficult
scholarship money they receive allows
them to focus on academics and training
at a high level
they are immensely grateful for your
support if you would consider giving
please visit griffins.ca
backslash dfc and give today
with your help and your contribution we
can help alleviate
some of the financial stresses that
student athletes go through
year in and year out let's do our part
and help these young people
shine in the classroom and on the
playing field
varsity athletics should never be about
pay to play
athletic scholarships can help to remove
some of the financial barriers our
athletes face on a daily basis
so that they can excel not only in their
sport
but in the classroom and out in our
communities as well
funds you provide will assist in
covering the cost
of books and tuition for our student
athletes
these student athletes are our future
leaders and i'm certain i can speak for
all of them when i express my gratitude
toward donors that keep our best
athletes here in canada for their
post-secondary schooling
please visit griffins.ca backslash
dfc thank you very much and go griffin
all right thank you coaches for the
messages and of course
capital paving our sponsor of the coach
videos
i also want to take an opportunity
because i know comments are still coming
in i think grace just said something
really really nice about me so grace
thank you for your kind words all right
i want to take
a moment to thank some of the sponsors
who made this challenge
possible again our title sponsor
manulife and td
insurance our presenting sponsor swish
maintenance
and then also our social media sponsors
richmond property
the hockey shop and champion mortgage
again
none of this happens without you thank
you so much for your generosity
and your sponsorship all right
our teams rely on the support of many
parents
and alumni and friends to help cheer
them on
on and off the field thanks to our
sponsors
smith and anderson we are going to hear
from some of those supporters
right now
[Music]
hi my name is susan frassen and i am the
proud mama of
two female athletes at the university of
guelph
it is great pleasure that i ask you
today to go on to
griffins.ca backslash dfc
and support the director's fundraising
challenge at the university of guelph
in support of women's athletic
scholarships i support griffin athletics
because i
truly believe that my experience as a
student athlete
has shaped me into the person i am today
i've made lifelong friends and memories
making my experience just truly
unforgettable
athletic scholarships reward the hard
work and skill of students and provide
them further opportunity to shine
at the core they financially assist
students who have met the prerequisites
and show potential for further success
why is it so important you ask well not
only do we need to bridge
huge inequity between male scholarships
and women's scholarships
but we also need to ensure that women
have every opportunity
to get the best education that they can
so they can improve life
join us in supporting griffin student
athletes by visiting
griffins.ca backslash
dfc it breaks my heart to think that
when the university of guelph are ranked
in the top 50 in the world for science
and technology
agricultural engineering veterinary
medicine it's such an amazing school
that a female athlete would have to turn
down that opportunity for an education
at the university of guelph because a
scholarship wasn't available to them
so you can change that go to griffins.ca
dfc and donate to support she's got game
and women's athletics
scholarships the university of guelph
and make a difference
in the life of griffin you won't regret
it
[Music]
all right thank you susan bill and
oliver and thank you to our
sponsor smith and anderson for those
lovely messages
all right so looks like we've had a
couple of more donations coming in so
we're going to look at our total and see
what that has
what that total has come to down here
below and it looks like it's 59
100 so great job folks thank you so much
for
the flooding of donations that have been
coming in and it just brings us closer
and closer to our goal again that is our
number
that is our clock almost five minutes
left to go here
and of course if you want to donate
griffins.ca
dfc again griffins.ca
dfc anything you can contribute we would
appreciate any and all support
all right so some griffins take their
sport to the next level after they leave
university because of the time and the
dedication they put towards their sport
while here at the university of guelph
so we have a few of those griffins here
to speak to you today
so we want to thank barzotti woodworking
our professional athlete sponsor
we have some very special guests here
with us today
[Music]
hey everyone my name is john rush i play
for the winnipeg blue bombers
and something you may not know about me
is i actually went to the university of
guelph and played football there
for five years one of the main reasons i
was able to do this
is because i was on scholarship and it
really meant the world to me
it meant that i was able to focus on
football it was it meant i was able to
focus on my training and it was really
one of the only reasons that i was
actually able to go to post-secondary
school so
it really meant a tremendous amount to
me and my family
to be able to receive a scholarship to
go to the university of guelph so
if you can if you have the means it
would really mean a lot to the programs
and i know the athletes if you could
donate and donate to the athletic
scholarship program so
thanks a lot for having me talk and have
yourselves a wonderful day hi everyone
i'm brit ben team canada rugby and
university of guelph alumna
i am asking you today to consider
supporting student athletes at the
university of guelph
through the manulife and td insurance
director's fundraising challenge
scholarships help change lives it allows
the student athletes to focus on their
school
training and sport thank you for your
consideration please visit
griffins.ca backslash dfc to give today
see ya hi i'm reed coolset guelph alumni
and two-time olympian
i'm here today asking you to consider
donating to the student athletes at the
university of guelph
through the director's fundraising
challenge scholarships are important at
the university of guelph to
keep our talent in canada without
scholarships
we lose a lot of talent i'm really happy
that i stayed in canada
and had a good progression through
the youth sport uh level and then
through the national level and then
eventually onto the olympics i'm glad
the option for
good training existed in canada and but
with scholarships it helps continue
those
um those legacies and to be competitive
within the youth sports system
um so once again that's uh griffins.ca
backslash dfc for the director's
fundraising challenge
and i hope to see you guys all soon okay
thanks a lot bye
hi guys i'm luke coral linebacker for
the hamilton tigercats
and proud university of guelph alumni
i'm asking you today
to help support our student athletes
through the manual life and td insurance
director's fundraising challenge
scholarships help change our athletes
lives and allows them to focus on their
schooling while still being able to
train towards their specific sport
if you could take the time today to go
to griffins.ca
dfc it would be very much appreciated
thank you so much
and all the best
[Music]
always nice to see a couple of familiar
faces ex-athletes here at the university
of guelph thank you
john luke britt and reed your support
means a lot to our athletes and we thank
you for taking the time out of your day
and joining us here today and of course
thanks again to barzotti woodworking for
sponsoring
our professional athlete videos all
right as you can see the clock above me
we're
at the two-minute warning uh appropriate
for sports of course
and we're close to the end here as the
keys weather clock
is ticking now i'd like to thank our
following sponsors for their ongoing
support all right so we have our digital
sponsor key sweater
excavating athlete sponsor ernst and
young llp
coach sponsor capital paving supporter
video sponsor smith and anderson
professional athlete sponsor barzotti
woodworking
launch video sponsor harbridge and cross
and
our supporting sponsor centaur products
again i cannot
emphasize enough about how much your
support means to us
and events like this don't happen
without you so thank you thank you thank
you thank you thank you
all right looks like we are minutes away
all right i can hear the clock ticking
we're minutes away from the end of our
challenge and our keysweater total
is 59 100. so 59 thousand
and 100 um
one second yeah for me
okay so i'll just read this
this just in oh along with
incredible donations and sponsorships
that we've received throughout this four
day
challenge we have received 161
500 of gift commitments for future
scholarships wow okay so i mean our
total's got to be absurd at this point
what's our new total
220 600 dollars we've raised for
athlete scholarships that is incredible
folks
round of applause great job what a great
day and
we're we're ticking here i've had so
much fun i don't want to leave
um i guess i'm going to take this time
to thank everyone that's made
this week possible our sponsors donors
alumni
coaches parents and of course our staff
behind the scenes that have made this
show a great success
this event and your contributions will
make a huge difference
difference for student athletes lives
and i've had such a blast being here and
it looks like
my time is up so what a great experience
folks thank you so much for taking time
out of your day
to hang out with us and of course
donating for such a great
uh cause i want to wish you all a
happy and healthy evening the weekend's
just around the corner and again it's
been such a blast for me
to be here with you this evening once
again thank you everyone
have a great night and go grips
[Music]
me
um
[Music]
you